

Gabriela Saldaña Aguilar

UX Designer | Mexico city

· CONTACT ·

gab.saldana95@gmail.com

525548811040

https://gabrielasaldana.github.io/profile/

· HARD SKILLS •

Data
Bases
REST Applicatio
Web
developme nt
Version
Control
Managers
User
Research
User
Testing
Wireframin
g

· SOFT SKILLS ·

English
Leadershi
p
Project
Managem
ent
Critical
thinking
Creativity
Collaborati
on
Product
Analysis



PROFILE

Experienced and self-motivated designer bringing two valuable industry knowledge. Problem solver oriented to results with proven record of working collaboratively with team members to achieve goals. Worked to align strategically technology, user desires and stakeholders needs trough my own learning.



EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science degree in Computer Systems Engineering from ESCOM - Instituto Politecnico Nacional



EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

User experience designer, Wizeline

March 2020 - May 2020

I participated in the migration plan of a big eco-system for a really big company. The challenge was to disappear the monolithic and legacy systems in order to bring a custom experience to the users instead of one big silo of user interface constrained by levels of accesses. I designed the new information architecture of each type of user based on ap previous user research.

Software Engineer, Wizeline

September 2019 - November 2019

These platforms helps to quote withing a wide range of carriers. I developed "Progressive" one of the 8 main auto insurance functionalities using python and selenium for the Back End and Angular for the Front End, we set up the distributed architecture using AWS services such as SQS and SNS this way you can increased concurrence between carriers.

Software Engineer-UI Designer, Wizeline

October 2018 - February 2019

Design, development, and delivery of a tax booking platform for a client in L.A California, the application categorizes and provides useful filtering and reporting to the expenses and incomes provided by a bank account from the user.

Freelancing

October 2017 - April 2018

I led the designing, development, and shipping of a reporter web application. I was the designer, technical writer, project manager, and developer of an online reporter tool that helped a company to make reports on the fly and outside the offices. They primarily use it for reporting trains issues on-site, since this company business was repairing trains.